Guide to the Doris Ulmann Photograph Collection ca. 1910-1934 PR 72
New-York Historical Society
- nine prisoners in field with hoes and buckets (Offsite-box 10, Box 19, Item 355)
- eight prisoners in field with hoes (Offsite-box 10, Box 19, Item 356)
- white woman in flowered dress sitting on bench among four black women and one black man (Offsite-box 10, Box 19, Item 357)
  from Leslie Chapman 1999 notes: #357-369 These images are scenes from the Harlem Renaissance play "Run Little Chillun" by Hall Johnson, which opened in the Lyric Theatre on March 1, 1933, also357-369 "theatrical production" per Margaret M. Clark notes1988
- gather of African Americans standing and on benches, white woman standing with hand raised (Offsite-box 10, Box 19, Item 358)
- men seated around standing man (Offsite-box 10, Box 19, Item 359)
- seated woman crying surrounded by five others (Offsite-box 10, Box 19, Item 360)
- man at pulpit and four men kneeling, praying (Offsite-box 10, Box 19, Item 361)
- man at pulpit, four men seated listening (Offsite-box 10, Box 19, Item 362)
- man gesticulating, raising hand in air, group of African Americans, one white man seated (Offsite-box 10, Box 19, Item 363)
- man gesticulating, raising hand in air, group of African Americans, one white man seated, same scene as 363 (Offsite-box 10, Box 19, Item 364)
- man at pulpit, four men seated around, four women kneeling in foreground (Offsite-box 10, Box 19, Item 365)
- white woman standing, group of African Americans standing and seated (Offsite-box 10, Box 19, Item 366)
- white woman in flowered dress, group of African Americans (Offsite-box 10, Box 19, Item 367)
- white woman, group of African Americans, same scene as 367 (Offsite-box 10, Box 19, Item 368)
- man at pulpit, four men kneeling (Offsite-box 10, Box 19, Item 369)
  from Leslie Chapman 1999 notes: #357-369 These images are scenes from the Harlem Renaissance play "Run Little Chillun" by Hall Johnson, which opened in the Lyric Theatre on March 1, 1933, also "theatrical production" per Margaret M. Clark notes1988
- group of people in field with baskets cutting asparagus (Offsite-box 10, Box 19, Item 370)
  #370, 2896 are different exposures from a scene in photo in RJR p28
- group of people in field with baskets cutting asparagus (Offsite-box 10, Box 20, Item 371)
- four black men in overalls sitting with frying pans (?) with very long handles, one white man in suit & tie & straw hat (Offsite-box 10, Box 20, Item 372)
- same group as 372, four black men in overalls sitting with frying pans (?) with very long handles, one white man in suit & tie & straw hat (Offsite-box 10, Box 20, Item 373)
- same group as 372, four black men in overalls sitting with frying pans (?) with very long handles, one white man in suit & tie & straw hat, one has a gun, so they may be hunting (Offsite-box 10, Box 20, Item 374)
- large group of men, a dozen or so, gathered outside of a store (Offsite-box 10, Box 20, Item 375)
- four men raking hay, one standing on a wagon (Offsite-box 10, Box 20, Item 376)
- group of women, men entering a school or church (Offsite-box 10, Box 20, Item 377)
- woman, three children, baby sitting on steps in doorway (Offsite-box 10, Box 20, Item 378)
- empty mat, no photo, see notes; four subjects; three seated working at a table bundling asparagus, white man (?) in background, two African American women in hats, jackets, white blouses; a very young white boy's head in lower right corner (Offsite-box 10, Box 20, Item 379)
  mat is empty (5/15/02), however a photo copy of this photo number is in the photo copy binder "Groups"
- women bundling asparagus, three white boys sitting in foreground (Offsite-box 10, Box 20, Item 380)
- group of women sitting and standing in church or a meeting (Offsite-box 10, Box 20, Item 381)
- large family in a wagon, two horses (Offsite-box 10, Box 20, Item 382)
- woman, three children, baby sitting on steps in doorway, same image as 378 (Offsite-box 10, Box 20, Item 383)
- four men gathered outside of a store (Offsite-box 10, Box 20, Item 384)
- three men (packers) with Dixie brand asparagus crates (Offsite-box 10, Box 20, Item 385)
  note in Ulmann's handwriting on back of mat: Packers 47
- group of men and women sitting at table praying (?), man reading from a book (Offsite-box 10, Box 20, Item 386)
- three women outside of cabin (Offsite-box 10, Box 20, Item 387)
  RJR per Margaret M. Clark notes, note in Ulmann's handwriting on back: "They say _____ _____ ____" 29
- Man standing in doorway, boy on steps and woman (Offsite-box 10, Box 20, Item 388)
- four women sitting in church (?) (Offsite-box 10, Box 20, Item 389)
- group of people sitting in church (Offsite-box 10, Box 20, Item 390)
- group of children, two adults on dirt road, several cabins (Offsite-box 11, Box 21, Item 391)
- group of people in field digging asparagus (Offsite-box 11, Box 21, Item 392)
- man, two boys with crates of Dixie brand asparagus (Offsite-box 11, Box 21, Item 393)
- three men weighing cotton in a field (Offsite-box 11, Box 21, Item 394)
- three men, one weaving a basket (Offsite-box 11, Box 21, Item 395)
- six young men crouching, playing a game on the ground (Offsite-box 11, Box 21, Item 396)
- boy with horse (Offsite-box 11, Box 21, Item 397)
- young man sitting on crate, basket of butchered chickens in foreground, 1917 (Offsite-box 11, Box 21, Item 398)
- smiling man in hat, glasses, white beard ["Old Man Greer, Singer of Carols", Owsley County, KY (see notes)] (Offsite-box 11, Box 21, Item 399)
  per Lesley Chapman 1999 notes, "Identified at UK as "Old Man Greer, singer of Carols", Owsley County KY
- man carrying bananas (Offsite-box 11, Box 21, Item 400)
- man weaving basket (Offsite-box 11, Box 21, Item 401)
- man with saw (Offsite-box 11, Box 21, Item 402)
- man sitting in doorway (Offsite-box 11, Box 21, Item 403)
- man with beard sitting in doorway (Offsite-box 11, Box 21, Item 404)
- man with beret (Offsite-box 11, Box 21, Item 405)
- man in overalls with hat (Offsite-box 11, Box 21, Item 406)
- young man in overalls in front of a building with vines (Offsite-box 11, Box 21, Item 407)
- man in overalls in barn (Offsite-box 11, Box 21, Item 408)
- man in field planting, horse or mule (Offsite-box 11, Box 21, Item 409)
- man on Farmall tractor in field (Offsite-box 11, Box 21, Item 410)
- man in straw hat, white shirt (Offsite-box 11, Box 22, Item 411)
- young man in work shirt (Offsite-box 11, Box 22, Item 412)
- man in suit and bow tie (Offsite-box 11, Box 22, Item 413)
  #413-419 same subject, James Weldon Johnson, identification per Lesley Chapman 1999 notes
- man in suit and bow tie standing at desk or pulpit (Offsite-box 11, Box 22, Item 414)
- man in suit and bow tie standing by chair (Offsite-box 11, Box 22, Item 415)
- man in suit and tie, sitting in chair [Johnson, James Weldon poet, diplomat, songwriter, and anthologist of black culture] (Offsite-box 11, Box 22, Item 416)
  #416-419, 1277, 1512, 1513, 1533-1536, 2031, 2069, 2216, 2236, 2237, 2238-2241, 2271, 2977, same subject
- man in suit and tie, sitting, with glasses [Johnson, James Weldon poet, diplomat, songwriter, and anthologist of black culture] (Offsite-box 11, Box 22, Item 417)
- man in suit and tie, sitting, with glasses [Johnson, James Weldon poet, diplomat, songwriter, and anthologist of black culture] (Offsite-box 11, Box 22, Item 418)
- man in suit and tie, sitting, writing at desk [Johnson, James Weldon poet, diplomat, songwriter, and anthologist of black culture] (Offsite-box 11, Box 22, Item 419)
- priest or monk in robe with hood, cross on chain around neck, beard (Offsite-box 11, Box 22, Item 420)
- priest or monk in robe, glasses, beard, shaved head, sitting, smiling (Offsite-box 11, Box 22, Item 421)
- priest or monk in robe, glasses, beard, shaved head, sitting, same man as 421 (Offsite-box 11, Box 22, Item 422)
- priest or monk in robe, glasses, beard, shaved head, sitting, same man as 421 (Offsite-box 11, Box 22, Item 423)
- priest or monk in robe, skullcap, in graveyard (Offsite-box 11, Box 22, Item 424)
- priest or monk in robe, skullcap, in arched doorway, same man as 424 (Offsite-box 11, Box 22, Item 425)
- priest or monk in robe, skullcap, entering arched doorway, doorway has two sets of carved skull and cross bones above doorway, same man as 424 (Offsite-box 11, Box 22, Item 426)
- hooded, robed priest or monk sitting in woods (Offsite-box 11, Box 22, Item 427)
- hooded, robed priest or monk walking in woods with back to camera, with walking stick, same man as 427 (Offsite-box 11, Box 22, Item 428)
- priest or monk in robe with hood, cross on chain around neck, beard, same man as 420, possibly same image as 420 (Offsite-box 11, Box 22, Item 429)
- two women in white clothing, sitting, third woman kneeling washing their feet (Offsite-box 11, Box 22, Item 430)
- African American man in white robes, white head covering (Item 431)
- African American man in white robes, white head covering, sitting, same man as 431 (Item 432)
- African American woman, nun, black robes, white collar and headdress (Item 433)
  RJR per Margaret M. Clark notes; per Leslie Chapman 1999 notes "#433, 438, 442, 443-444, 447-450 These images are all of nuns at the convent of the Sister of the Holy Family in New Orleans, Louisiana, which was, according to the Getty's 'In Focus' series
- African American man in white robes, white head covering, sitting, same man as 431 (Item 434)
- African American man in white robes, white head covering, standing in front of climbing rose bush, same man as 431 (Item 435)
- African American man in white robes, white head covering, standing in front of climbing rose bush, same man as 431 (Item 436)
- woman pulling rope (for a bell?) (Item 437)
- woman, nun, black robe, white collar, headdress, sitting, holding small child (Item 438)
  Nuns; New Orleans per Margaret J. Clark; per Leslie Chapman 1999 notes "#433, 438, 442, 443-444, 447-450 These images are all of nuns at the convent of the Sister of the Holy Family in New Orleans, Louisiana, which was, according to the Getty's 'In Foc
- woman, nun, black robe, white collar, headdress (Item 439)
  Nuns; New Orleans per Margaret J. Clark notes
- woman, nun, black robe, white collar, headdress, same woman as 439 (Item 440)
- nun standing in garden (Item 441)
- African American nun (Item 442)
  Nuns; New Orleans per Margaret J. Clark notes; per Leslie Chapman 1999 notes "#433, 438, 442, 443-444, 447-450 These images are all of nuns at the convent of the Sister of the Holy Family in New Orleans, Louisiana, which was, according to the Getty's 'In
- two African American nuns (Item 443)
- African American nun standing with young girl (Item 444)
- three nuns standing in garden reading (Item 445)
- four nuns seated in garden (Item 446)
- African American nun sitting with two young African American boys (Item 447)
- nun seated in garden with four African American girls who are wearing what look like school uniforms (Item 448)
- nun in garden with large group of African American children who are wearing what look like school uniforms, on girl in white dress (Item 449)
- nun in garden with large group of African American children who are wearing what look like school uniforms, on girl in white dress, same group as 449 (Item 450)
- man in suit and tie, sitting, holding book, same man as 416 [Johnson, James Weldon (see notes)] (Item 451)
  identification of image 416 per Lesley Chapman 1999 notes, monogram very faint; also per Margaret M. Clark "James Weldon Johnson, d. 1938, possibly taken 1930"
- man in suit and tie, holding booklet (Item 452)
- man in suit and tie, holding booklet, same man as 452 (Item 453)
- African American man in suit and tie, raised arms, preacher at pulpit (Item 454)
- African man in suit with woven shawl over suite, white hair, fez with tassel [Bata Kindai Amgoza Lo Bagolo] (Item 455)
  #455, 727, 1391,1401-1408, 1410, 2952; subject's name in handwriting (not DU) on back of mats 1401-1408, 1410
- man sitting with violin or fiddle (Item 456)
- man in white shirt and vest, white hair, beard, and mustache (Item 457)
- man in cap (Item 458)
- elderly man sitting on porch holding walking stick (Item 459)
- man with white shirt and hat holding handles to a wheelbarrow (Item 460)
- man in straw hat, black vest, white shirt, mustache (Item 461)
- man in overalls, cap, right hand is bandaged (Item 462)
- ornate domed building in background, 1917 (Item 463)
- courtyard garden (Item 464)
- stone doorway with cross at top, a vault in cemetery (Item 465)
- stone doorway with cross at top, a vault in cemetery, same image as 465 (Item 466)
- cabin, woman in doorway (Item 467)
- large house, columned porches, live oak, moss (Item 468)
- wooden dock in small town, from water (Item 469)
- wooden dock in small town, from water (Item 470)
- wooden building, four square columns, tin roof (Item 471)
- formal garden or park, monument from back of standing man with robe, chair, 1919 (Item 472)
- formal garden or park, monument (same as 472) front view of standing man with robe, chair, apartment building in background, 1919 (Item 473)
- stone stairway, railing (Item 474)
- stone doorway with cross at top, a vault in cemetery, looks like same image as 465 (Item 475)
- brick arched passageway, stairs, ivy (Item 476)
  "Johns Hopkins's, Book of Portraits, Frontispiece" per Margaret M. Clark's notes 1988
- large domed institutional building, car in front (Item 477)
- large house on hill with porch (Item 478)
- capitol dome in Washington DC at night with palms (Item 479)
- river, marsh, hills (Item 480)
- white wooden church with steeple (Item 481)
- church or chapel interior (Item 482)
- church or chapel interior, looks like same image as 482 (Item 483)
- wooden barrels stacked at warehouse or dock (Item 484)
- barn or garage on hillside (Item 485)
  486-488, same image as RJRp63
- cemetery, oak trees, moss (Item 486)
  486-488 RJR per Margaret M. Clark's notes 1988
- cemetery, oak trees, moss, possibly same image as 486 (Item 487)
- cemetery, oak trees, moss, possibly same image as 486 (Item 488)
- wood lattice structure with gravestone carved with hand and "GONE HOME" (Item 489)
- wood lattice structure with gravestone carved with hand and "GONE HOME", same image as 489 (Item 490)
- net or yarn rolled on a wheel in a yard (Item 491)
- boats docked (Item 492)
- boat with sail partly raise, in dock (Item 493)
- small boats docked in harbor (Item 494)
  note on back of mat in Ulmann's handwriting: Doris Ulmann 1000 Park Avenue New York City, Boats, IV, ac
- boat with sail partly raise, in dock, same image as 493 (Item 495)
- clothes blowing in wind on clothesline in farm yard, young girl leaning on wooden barrel (Item 496)
- clothes blowing in wind on clothesline in farm yard, young girl leaning on wooden barrel, same image as 496 (Item 497)
- stalactite and stalagmite cavern (Item 498)
- stalactite and stalagmite cavern, same image as 499 (Item 499)
- boy, girl, man (Item 500)
- boy, girl, man, same group as 500 (Item 501)
- two elderly women, seated in white aprons, one with crutch (Item 502)
- boy, girl, man, same group as 500 (Item 503)
- little girl, big white bow in her hair, ruffled white blouse (Item 504)
  same image as RJRp221
- two men with wagon in large loading area or yard (Item 505)
- man in topcoat and hat, night street scene with auto, 1916 (Item 506)
  similar image 119, note on back of mat in Ulmann's handwriting: "'Midnight' Doris U. Jaeger 129 West 86th Street N.Y. City"
- girl in long dress and bonnet in interior, rocking chair, chest of drawers with framed photos (Item 507)
- people in tilled field, woman in foreground with large straw hat and hoe (Item 508)
- two men with wagon, same image as 505 (Item 509)
- man's hands--bending a piece of wood (?) (Item 510)
- man or monk standing in black robes on stone in hillside (Item 511)
- nun in long outdoor colonnade (Item 512)
- man's hands on desk with book (Item 513)
- two craftsmen or workmen with small bellows, partial torsos, hands, and arms only (Item 514)
- men gathered, sitting in front of building (Item 515)
  in Ulmann's handwriting on back "71 The Country Store"
- monk or priest in robe, raising arms, standing on rock on hillside (Item 516)
- brick/stucco cemetery vaults (Item 517)
- man with hoe and pipe, arms, hands, torso only (Item 518)
- man's hands on desk with book, same subject as 513 (Item 519)
- young woman with hat sitting in farm yard (Item 520)
- two women with apples, one woman with a bandage on her arm (Item 521)
- two women with apples, one woman with a bandage on her arm, same women as 521 (Item 522)
- young woman, seated, blouse with ruffles (Item 523)
- wood workers, hands and arms only (Item 524)
- man with hoe and pipe, arms, hands, torso only, same as 518 (Item 525)
- wood worker's hands (Item 526)
- older, with hat, long white beard, mustache, sideburns, possibly a minister, seated with book, dark suit (Item 527)
- minister, glasses, white hair and short white beard, with book (Item 528)
  from Lesley Chapman notes 1999: #530 According to the Getty, a Dunkard minister in Ephrata, Pennsylvania c1925-27--if this is the case, the #528-29 are also Dunkard men.
- two ministers sitting, with book (Item 529)
- minister, white hair, long white beard with book (Item 530)
  from Lesley Chapman notes 1999: #530 According to the Getty, a Dunkard minister in Ephrata, Pennsylvania c1925-27--if this is the case, the #528-29 are also Dunkard men.; from Margaret M Clark notes July 19, 1988 "The Mentor", (July 1927) minister at Eph
- hands, straw hat (Item 531)
- young boy, smiling, in overalls with straw hat (Item 532)
- boy with cap in overalls, two pails (Item 533)
- boy with oversized waterproof vest and hat, fishing pole (tree branch with knotted rope) (Item 534)
- seated boy with oversized waterproof vest and hat, fishing pole (tree branch), same boy as 534 (Item 535)
- boy sitting on ground, among shrubs, leaves (Item 536)
- seated boy with oversized waterproof vest and hat, fishing pole (tree branch), same boy as 534 (Item 537)
- young girl, short cropped brown hair in dress or smock with piping (Item 538)
- boy with big straw hat, how, pail, in overalls (Item 539)
- blonde baby in chair on porch (Item 540)
- seated boy with oversized waterproof vest and hat, fishing pole (tree branch), same boy as 534 (Item 541)
- boy in sailor's suit on toy horse (Item 542)
- boy in overalls and cap at water pump with pails (Item 543)
- boy in with shirt with overalls leaning on a fence (?) (Item 544)
- girl with ringlets, looks like much earlier time period than the twenties, old print or reprint of old negative? (Item 545)
  could this be Ulmann?
- boy in white shirt and shorts (Item 546)
- boy in white shirt and shorts, standing, same boy as 546 (Item 547)
- boy in overalls, tattered sweater, straw hat, holding an apple, leaning on post (Item 548)
- boy with oversized waterproof vest and hat, fishing pole (tree branch with knotted rope), possibly same image as 534 (Item 549)
- seated boy with oversized waterproof vest and hat, fishing pole (tree branch), same boy as 534, possibly same image as 535 (Item 550)
- seated boy with oversized waterproof vest and hat, fishing pole (tree branch), same boy as 534, possibly same image as 536 (Item 551)
- seated boy with oversized waterproof vest and hat, fishing pole (tree branch), same boy as 534 (Item 552)
- boy holding a bowl, standing outside of stable door with harnesses hanging on the side of the building (Item 553)
  note on back in Ulmann's handwriting: 81 The Barn Door
- boy with big straw hat, how, pail, in overalls, same boy as 539 (Item 554)
  in Ulmann's handwriting on back: 59 Tom
- boy in striped shirt seated among rocks and ferns (Item 555)
- boy in overalls, checked shirt with pail on small horse or pony (Item 556)
- boy in overall with stick/pole with a bandana tied to it as a bundle (Item 557)
- street scene, side building, 1917 (Item 558)
- large stone church with columns and steeple, 1917 (Item 559)
- street scene, side of large house, 1917 (Item 560)
- porch, brick house, palm trees (Item 561)
- cottage with porch (Item 562)
- curving stone or stucco stairway to porch, ivy (Item 563)
- front of church or meeting house (Item 564)
- small, narrow street, looks like New Orleans (Item 565)
- large institutional building [Johns Hopkins University Building] (Item 566)
  a photogravure, looks like it came out of a book, note on back says: Johns Hopkins Hospital, Baltimore, Md.
  A Book of Portraits (Johns Hopkins University, 1922)
- house on canal, boat (Item 567)
- large stone church with columns and steeple, same building, possibly same image as 559, 1917 (Item 568)
- house on canal, boat, same house as 567 (Item 569)
- two story brick house (Item 570)
- park, monument, New York City, Metropolitan Life tower on Madison Square in background, 1919 (Item 571)
  looks like Gramercy park
- stucco farmhouse with sloped shingled roof (Item 572)
- Capitol dome, Washington DC at night (Item 573)
- large stone church with columns and steeple, same building, possibly same image as 559, 1917 (Item 574)
- plantation house with porch, live oak, moss (Item 575)
- corner of large house, two story porch, looks southern (Item 576)
- corner of large house, two story porch, looks southern, same house as 576 (Item 577)
- two story brick house, same house as 570, possibly same image (Item 578)
- garden courtyard (Item 579)
  one of at least three images of the same garden
- doorway, window, ivy covered (Item 580)
- hillside, curving road, farm buildings (Item 581)
- brick wall, side of brick building, garden (Item 582)
- park, monument, New York City, Metropolitan Life tower on Madison Square in background, same image as 571, 1919 (Item 583)
  looks like Gramercy Park
- lumberyard (Item 584)
- lumberyard with buildings, man working (Item 585)
- church steeple (Item 586)
- small town, church steeple (Item 587)
- lumberyard, buildings, large uncut logs, man climbing ladder (Item 588)
- porch, windows, 1918 (Item 589)
  In Ulmann's handwriting on back: Design, Doris U. Jaeger, 129 West 86th St., N.Y. City
- two story wooden house (Item 590)
- large brick and stone institutional building, 1917 (Item 591)
  In Ulmann's handwriting on back: Avery (???), Doris U. Jaeger, 129 West 86th St., N.Y. City
- building through elevated rail road tracks, 1918 (Item 592)
- large stone bell tower, 4-5 stories high, looks like a college campus, 1917 (Item 593)
- seated, gown with beaded straps, short curly dark hair [Widdeman, Margaret] (Item 594)
  #594-597, 646-647, 800-806 same subject; identification is per MM Clark
- velvet gown, lace collar [Widdeman, Margaret] (Item 595)
- velvet gown, lace collar [Widdeman, Margaret] (Item 596)
- gown with beaded straps, tulips [Widdeman, Margaret] (Item 597)
- head and shoulders from side, long hair in bun (Item 598)
- older woman, white hair, glasses, tatting or mending, sewing basket on table, image of William Shakespeare on wall in background, 1917 (Item 599)
- seated woman, short dark hair, dress with lace collar, pearls (Item 600)
  # 600-601 same woman
- with make up, dressed hair, sheer shawl, long seed pearl necklace, very elegant (Item 601)
  # 600-601, 624 same woman
- seated, dark dress with long beaded necklace [Peterkin, Julia] (Item 602)
  same sitting as images in Jacobs book, pages 61 & 200
- flower print gown [Peterkin, Julia] (Item 603)
  notes from Margaret M. Clark July 19, 1988: in costume for production of Hedda Gabler, see Theatre Arts Monthly, July 1932 p. 602
- glamorous looking, mid-thirties, pearls, short hair, dark dress with white satin pleated collar (Item 604)
- two middle-aged (?) women, one standing (dark hair) putting hand on eyes of seated woman (lighter, curled, short hair) [Keller, Helen, on right] (Item 605)
  second woman might be Anne Sullivan